Julio Cesar Ramirez Paredes

Profile

Bachelor of civil engineering, expert in engineering solutions for fluid mechanics and computational fluid dynamics in challenging problems.

Interest in fluid mechanics and programming languages.

Outstanding learning capacity, motivation to continue learning and orientation to achieve results in my career.

Social Network

- **J** (+51) 939196012
- ✓ julio.ramirez@pucp.edu.pe
- in Linkedin
- Github
- Pucp
- **@** Website
- Resume

Languages

English Portuguese

Programming

C++
Fortran
Python

EDUCATION

Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú
Bachelor's Degree in Civil Engineering

San Miguel ,PE Jul 2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú

San Miguel, PE

Teaching Assistant

Mar 2019 - Current

• Fluid mechanics and hydraulics laboratory: Experimental and theoretical knowledge of conversation laws, hydrostatics, ship stability, hydraulic jump, weirs, non-newtonian fluids, pumps and pipes.

• Hidro Mayu

Barranco, PE

Hydraulic equipment training

May 2023

 Fluid mechanics: Installation and training to teachers and students about the equipment of the Universidad de Ingenieria y Tecnologia's hydraulics laboratory

• Hidro Mayu

Chiclayo, PE

Hydraulic equipment maintenance support

Nov 2022

 Fluid mechanics: Maintenance and training to teachers and students about the equipment of the Universidad Catolica Santo Toribio de Mogrovejo's hydraulics laboratory

• Hidro Mayu

Lambayeque, PE

Structural equipment installation assistant

Mar 2023

• Mechanics of materials and structural analysis: Training to teachers about the equipment of the Universidad Nacional Pedro Ruiz Gallo's structural engineering laboratory

Hidro Mayu

Huacho, PE

Hydraulic equipment maintenance support

Nov 2022

- Fluid mechanics and open channel hydraulics: Maintenance and training to teachers and students about the equipment of the Universidad Nacional Jose Faustino Sanchez Carrion's hydraulics laboratory
- Centro de Investigación y Tecnología del Agua Barranco, PE Research Assistant Sep 2019 - Nov 2021
 - **Urban air quality**: Numerical simulation of the navier equations for incompresible newtonian flow in air fluid in urban environments using Openfoam.
 - Dam break: Numerical modeling of the shallow water equation for incompresible newtonian flow in dam break escenarios using Telemac-2D.
- Universidad de Ingeniería y Tecnologia

Barranco, PE

Teaching Assistant

Aug 2019 - Nov 2021

- Mathematics III: Solid understanding of linear algebra and numerical methods.
- Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú

San Miguel, PE

Jefe de Práctica

Mar 2019 - Jul 2020

- Open Channel Hydraulics: Solid understading of channel morphology, hydraulic engineering and sediment transport.
- MJ & Asociados Water Resources Consulting Lima, PE

Practicing civil engineer

Mar 2019 - Jun 2019

• **River flood**: Observation of flood zone in the Moquegua river under extreme flood condition to investigate the resilience of the infrastructure.

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- **Programming Languages**: C++, C, Fortran, Python, R, Javascript, Scilab, Matlab, CSS, HTML, Bash y Lisp.
- Softwares: Hecras, Telemac, Flo-2D, River2D, OpenFOAM, Qgis, Arcgis, Emacs, Pointwise, Tecplot, Blender, Autocad, Latex, Ubuntu, Git y Aws.
- Tiping: Typing speed of 65 wpm Monkeytype, Keybr.

Courses

• Master python for data science

• Programming CFD OpenFOAM

• Fire modelling with OpenFOAM

• OpenFOAM turbulence

• Autocad 2018 advanced

• OpenFOAM advanced

• Open source hydraulics modelling of shallow water flow

inLearning 2021

CFD Direct 2021

OpenFOAM 2020

CFD Support 2019

CFD Support 2019

Universidad Nacional de Ingeniería Hydraulics Laboratory 2018

Centro de Cómputo UNIMASTER 2018